# Damien Aries

Web Developer
JavaScript | React | Node

San Gabriel, CA (917) 921 – 1162 damien.aries@gmail.com www.damienaries.com LinkedIn Github

CONTACT

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Quality-oriented professional with 15+ years of bar experience, six of which as manager or lead. Today as a developer I am taking my career in a new direction while putting to use the invaluable skills I acquired in the hospitality industry, with the goal to help develop useful ethical technologies.

# **SKILLS**

- HTML \ CSS \ SCSS \ Bootstrap \ Material UI
- JavaScript, TypeScript, React
- Express, Node, MongoDB, Firebase, AWS
- Figma \ Wireframing
- Knowledge of Responsive Web Design and accessibility best practices
- Self starter, always looking to improve and eager to learn
- Dedicated and flexible team member
- Excellent written and oral communication skills
- Strong organizational and analytical skills
- Creative problem solver, result oriented
- Used to work in Agile teams in multiples timezones
- Languages: French (Mother tongue) | English
   (Bilingual) | Italian & Spanish (Conversational)

# **PROJECTS**

# **Loving Dog Sitter - Hatchways**

Hatchways.io offers coding assessments for companies and developers. As part of this agile work simulation, I worked on building this dog sitting marketplace in TypeScript, React, MongoDB, AWS, Material UI

Github

#### BlogR - Front End Mentor

A simple responsive landing page for a fictional publishing company, built in React with Styled Components.

Live Site - Github

# **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer (Internship)

# **CONCEPT.APP**

Concept is a social platform for human flourishing built in JavaScript, React and Firebase. My role there as a member of the startup's founding dev team was distributed across the stack, with a Front-End focus to build foundational features like a forum page and our onboarding slides.

January 2021 - July 2021

Brand Ambassador - Southern California

#### Ron Colon Salvadoreño

January 2020 - December 2020

Head Bartender

Here And Now, Los Angeles, CA

November 2019 - March 2020

Bar and Operations Manager

Her Name Was Carmen - New York, NY

November 2018 - July 2019

General Manager and Co-Founder

Colibri - New York, NY

August 2017 - September 2018

Head Bartender

Loosie Rouge - Brooklyn, NY

April 2016 - June 2017

General Manager & Bartender

# **Experimental Cocktail Group**

New York, NY - June 2014 - March 2016 Paris, France - September 2012 – June 2014

# **EDUCATION**

Web Development Courses:

**CodeCademy** - Web Development Career Path

FreeCodeCamp - Responsive Web Design

**Udemy** - Web Development Bootcamp

**Udemy** - React Developer Bootcamp

Bachelor's degree - English and Italian translation Universities of Nantes, France & Lecce, Italy